Register of the Obshchestudencheskii russkii khor imeni A. A. Arkhangel'skogo Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Obshchestudencheskiĭ russkiĭ khor imeni A. A. Arkhangel'skogo records,
1916-1968
2000C87
Obshchestudencheskii russkii khor imeni A. A. Arkhangel'skogo
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, minutes, printed matter, and photographs, relating to émigré Russian choir activities in Czechoslovakia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Administrative History
Russian student choir in Prague.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists mainly of correspondence and printed matter relating to the activities of the A. A. Arkhangel'skii Russian Student Choir in Prague in the 1920s. Most of the correspondence is in the form of congratulations and invitations, some from well-known figures in Czechoslovakia, such as Alice Masaryk. The scrapbook contains a history of the choir and biographical information on Arkhangel'skii and successive conductors.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Choral societies--Czechoslovakia.; Russians--Czechoslovakia.; Russia.; Czechoslovakia.
Other Index Terms Related to this Collection
Arkhangel'skii, Aleksandr Andreevich, 1846-1924.
Series Description
- Office File, 1916-1968. (Box 1)
  Correspondence, minutes of meetings, posters, printed matter, scrapbook and photographs, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Photographs, 1917-1947. (Box 1)
  25 prints, 2 negatives and 6 print reproductions, primarily of the entire choir and individual singers and conductors, including several portraits of Arkhangel'skii
Container List
- OFFICE FILE, 1916-1968. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1916-1958., See also Scrapbook (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes letters and cards to and from choir collective as well as conductors and executives, including A. A. Arkhangel'skii.
  - Minutes of meetings of the Commission to organize the celebration of the Choir's fifth anniversary (Folder 1: 2)
  - Posters (Folder 1: 3-4)
  - Printed matter
    - General., See also Scrapbook (Folder 1: 5)
      Includes clippings, programs, and advertising matter.
    - Russkii khorovoi viestnik, #1-10 (1928) (Folder 1: 6)
  - Scrapbook. (Folder 1: 7)
    Includes a history of the Choir, compiled in 1950, advertisements, Arkhangel'skii's notes, biographical information on the Choir's conductors, clippings, correspondence, photographs, and other matter
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1917-1947., See also Scrapbook (Folder 1: 8)
  25 prints, 2 negatives and 6 print reproductions, primarily of the entire choir and individual singers and conductors, including several portraits of Arkhangel'skii.